hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and if we haven't met
yet i've been helping course creators
trainers authors speakers for the last
19 years get more customers and grow
their businesses to seven and eight
figures and i want to help you today
listen even if you're just getting
started you might be like well i'm not
even close to making a million dollars i
just want to make my first thousand
dollars i just want to make my first
sale
as a course creator or coach or author
and you want to know how to do it
through the internet you've come to the
right place this is going to be the
ultimate beginners lesson for you on
marketing so my background is in what's
called direct response marketing direct
response marketing is a little bit
different than just traditional
marketing traditional marketing has to
do with
graphic design and and campaigns on on
billboards and in magazines online
direct response marketing is what i
specialize in which is we put out
campaigns on the internet usually social
media
most of the time social media but we
also
use the social media to get people on
our email list over to our website to
then get them to sign up and purchase a
book
buy a course become a customer become a
client that way and so that's what this
episode is all about is using online
social media based direct response
marketing if you're just getting started
there's really two things that i tell
everybody that they need to do that they
need to start with the first one
super simply
is daily social media video if you're
not posting videos on social media
that's the number one place to start and
you can actually check out over at my my
instagram
uh at instagram.com forward slash jeremy
crack i'm actually gonna share the the
screen here this is my instagram i post
every single day at least three videos
a graphic a day a photo
but the goal of all of my content is to
connect with you a course creator a
coach a trainer an author to help you
make twenty thousand thirty thousand
forty thousand a month or even your
first
500 bucks
whatever it is that you want to do
that's what my social media is all about
okay so that's what i coach people on
that's what i teach that's what i help
people do
so all of my content is based on the
people that i've worked with the
thousands of people over the years that
i've worked with what they need to know
to get started and over at my podcast at
jeremiahkowski.com
this podcast right here that you're
listening to we have over
164 episodes on everything about direct
response marketing
that course creators coaches trainers
need okay so think of it that way that's
you i'm talking about what my business
is you're like well jeremiah i don't do
that i i help people
deal with their nutrition after they've
had a life-saving cancer treatment or or
i help
restaurateurs
know how to run their social media
i get it
you're you're not in the same business
that i am and here's the thing i'm gonna
i'm gonna actually
dispel a myth for you
and probably give you some news that's
to make you very happy
you don't need to be an expert in
marketing to be able to be successful
as a coach
as a course creator as a trainer as an
author in fact
i would highly recommend you not because
honestly you're gonna waste a lot of
time trying to learn
all the stuff about marketing
you do what you do best coach people
train them teach them
help them get results and transformation
in their lives and and if you've never
taught somebody coached before or
trained somebody i do have courses on my
website about creating your first course
starting your own coaching program
but what i love helping people do is not
just how do they make what their craft
is better
how do they make more money doing that
how do they make
twenty thousand thirty thousand even a
million dollars
doing that
that's what my social media is all about
so that's what i help people do people
just like you
increase their income
ask yourself this question
what do you help people do
specifically
what result do you deliver
we have to start with results first
who are you helping
what result do they desire in their life
it's the first question you gotta answer
and i actually have a series of
questions that i ask people when i'm
doing an assessment of their business
when i'm coaching them when they're one
of my one-on-one coaching clients and
this series of questions if you write
these down and start to answer them
can really help you
identify exactly how to market to those
people and how to reach them to become
your customers okay
so this is the first step that we start
with a lot of people are like well okay
i know i need to post on social media
but what do i post here's the answer to
that
i want you to answer these questions who
is your customer really sit with it you
know they could be a female professional
ceo that's making six figures they love
to travel go to the spas whole foods
know that's a type of person a very
specific type of person one of my
clients that's what hers are
now answer this
what are their biggest problems
that you most know of
that you help solve
so for this client they have no energy
they
have weight gain they
struggle to go to the bathroom they have
a high stress life they have trouble
sleeping
they they are gaining weight and don't
know why okay and so she helps people
those women
solve that problem
okay she helps them take back their life
to no longer feel fatigued stressed out
so they can live the life that they've
always dreamed of and she does so with
courses and training and webinars and
coaching and testing and different
things like that which is awesome
her best clients literally have a 180 in
their life
okay so as you begin to understand who
your customer is and here's a few more
questions you know what are they most
afraid of
a lot of times
your clients are afraid that what you do
will not work for them
if you're listening to me right now
maybe you've listened to another trainer
another podcast
one of your biggest
fears might be that
it's not going to work for you that
you're not going to be successful and
it's just the same way with those that
you help and they're going to spend a
lot of money with you and get no results
and so your job when you're marketing is
to solve that problem for them
is to help them
is to help alleviate
those
sticking points that stop people from
making the buying decision and so that's
where your social media what you do is
you think about okay who is this person
who is this type of person
what solutions can i offer them and this
is where i think course creators and
coaches
miss it is that
they keep so much of their secret sauce
behind the scenes
they don't share
openly
publicly the stuff that really produces
results they they hold it in they bottle
it up and and and what they put on
social media content is very surface
level
it's very
not really going to change somebody's
life it's just a teaser
and and that's not going to work
you have to put your best content
that you charge people money for
for free on social media
now usually when i say that people are
either intrigued or they are
pissed off
because it's challenges the way that
they've thought about things i'm telling
you this my friends the way that you're
going to make the most amount of money
even your first 500 bucks is by doing
exactly that
by doing exactly that putting your best
content out there for free
the very best stuff
that you can help people with
for free you might say well if i do that
what am i going to charge money for then
we'll get there so here's the thing
that's what i teach people how to do in
my courses that's what i show you how to
do throughout this podcast if you listen
through my podcast
i'm going to show you
how to do that exactly that but i'm
actually going to give it to you right
now
how to do it
and that my friends is exactly how you
can do it is you is you point to the
fact that you do teach this you do
charge for it some of you would be
afraid to give it away for free and also
charge for the same content
and you're supposed to
that's exactly what you're supposed to
do you're supposed to give away the best
content and charge for the exact same
content
and this is where a lot of people
they almost feel guilt they feel worried
they feel shame they feel like that's
unethical to do
it's not
it's not it's not it's not
because here's the thing
the people that don't invest with you
are only going to get a very surface
level of transformation in their life
they're only going to get a small piece
of what you share and here's what you do
you share your best content that's at
the beginning stage of their journey
with them
the beginning stage
as you walk with people
figure out
what level are they not getting with you
and charge for that
okay so i could give away all of my
content on how to build a business in
fact my podcast has it all it's all free
literally put
everything i know into my podcast
but there's certain lessons that people
resonate with more than others this is
one of them a lot of people really like
when i teach
this lesson
when i teach about self-discipline and
motivation and how to keep yourself
motivated to do the work i get
very few people that actually listen to
that content in my free training so i
continue to reiterate that in my paid
training and then people start to get it
see the results are produced by the
actions they take i'm saying the same
message
but i'm meeting them at a different
place in their life journey in their
coaching journey
and so
your goal is give away all your best
content for free
just give it away
and then have offers that you charge for
that take people
to the next step of
the limit
of their ability
to do it on their own without
accountability
you see what i'm saying so what you're
going to look at is if i have a group of
500 people they go through all my best
content right
where's the point where most of them end
up getting stuck
and they don't do anything and even
though i've shared it until i'm blue in
the face they still don't do anything
i'm telling you
it happens all the time
that's what i
have in my courses
that's what i have in my
coaching
as the same for you so what you do is
you give away all your best content and
then you figure out where is the point
where people are getting stuck
and can't seem to break through with
that free content and that's what you
charge money for okay so how do you then
reach these people well you got to have
some way for them to give you their
money
online
so they meet you on social media
and you have an offer that you make them
whether it be a free training
that they have to give their email
address for
so you can teach the same stuff that's
on your social media but in exchange for
an email address
it's it's it's way simpler than most
people are making it
that's why most people struggle
in this business
and when people are on your email list
then you are able to
market to them through email and people
are more likely to sign up for
and purchase what you're selling when
they're on your email list because
you're nurturing connection and
relationship now on your website you
have a variety of different things that
you offer people you have different
offers
and we're going to get to what's the
difference between a funnel and a
website do i need a website is a funnel
enough
i'm gonna get there
on there you have offers that connect
with
who the person is we answered those
questions who's your customer what
problem do they have what solution do
you offer
what solution can they pay you money for
what's the best result what are they
most afraid of
what secret desires do they have what
are their top frustrations
and how does that connect with your
experience and the coaching that you
offer them and the case studies of
clients that you've helped
and then you deliver that
as offers okay and then in those offers
you
have another offer not a free one but a
paid one something that you charge money
for
something that you charge a hundred
dollars for five hundred dollars a
thousand dollars for
that people give you their money and
sign up for to go through a course
a coaching program an accountability
program something
that will promise
a transformative result in their life
and so you reach people through social
media you send them to your website to
your offer
they go through your funnel
on your website
and they end up
buying from you and by the way only a
small percentage actually buy from you
less than five percent
of anybody who actually
sees you on social media is gonna buy
from you
and that's normal that's by design
you might say well the other 95 like
what about them
they got value from your content but
they're not exactly your target customer
and so niching down is very important
finding your niche identifying
what is the number one
area of transformation and result that i
can help people with and then building
your whole business around that on your
social media on your offers on your
website and what you have for sale
and by doing this
you're able to reach
thousands
millions of people that you've never met
before
to
direct them to something that will bring
a result in their life
that they've always desired
that they've always wanted
and when you do this
you have an opportunity
to direct them to
a next step where they can buy from you
and this is where a lot of course
graders and coaches
also miss it as they are nervous when it
comes to asking people to sign up with
an email address or to give money to
them
for whatever reason they
they don't want to be slimy and salesy
my friends i'm gonna i'm gonna give you
some wisdom here
you're not going to be
most course graders and coaches
are not slimy and salesy especially the
ones who i work with
because of the integrity that they have
the desire that they have to impact and
help people
and so actually learning how to connect
with people
influence that let me ask you this am i
being slimy and salesy right now in this
video
no
i'm asking you to just do the same thing
i'm doing right now
and by doing that you're able to lead
people
to what you have to offer
and that is the beginning steps
as a course creator as a coach now you
might see these ads out there that say
russell brunson has you don't need a
website you only need a funnel the truth
is
a funnel
is technically a website it's just a
single landing page it's just a one page
with something that people sign up for
and then you lead people to other offers
inside of that okay i still prefer as a
course creator as a coach i think that
you do need to have some kind of a home
page something like what i have here
over at my website jeremiahkowski.com
that links to
other offers you have like a facebook
group a podcast
blog post your email list courses that
you have i have all my courses on here
that you can check out over at my
website copy and funnel audit you can
get a trial of one of my favorite tools
that i think course creators and coaches
need to use jasper it's an artificial
intelligence tool that helps you write
your marketing copy for you to help you
write the words that get people to sign
up for you that helps you come up with
ideas for your social media content with
ai
and it's one of the best tools i know of
so my friends
a funnel is essentially just a page like
this
a landing page of some kind that has
some testimonies it has
some features it has a story and if you
want to know how to build out pages like
this and how to build out landing pages
and offers again my podcast
talks about that as well as my course
irresistible offers that sell my course
website building made easy all over at
my website at jeremiah.com listen if
you're a course creator coach trainer
author and you're just getting started
in your business and you're like
what do i do next keep listening to this
podcast keep plugging into the nearly 1
000 videos that i have over on youtube
that teach you the very best content
that i have on exactly what you need to
do to market
and reach customers so that you can get
people
buying your paid programs this year
there's no excuse for you to be
struggling my friends
plug in
learn what you can grow in skills
and i keep it very basic very simple
just the stuff you need to know
i think it's really going to help you
all right that's my sales pitch right
there it wasn't slimy it wasn't sleazy
it wasn't anything that was like
yuck i just want to see you succeed
and so if i can tell you about
the different ways that are free on my
website
that are low-cost extremely affordable
ways extremely affordable one-on-one
coaching where i can help come alongside
you and help you build your business
then i've done my job
and i can help you impact thousands of
people with your job
see i believe course creators coaches
and trainers change the world they write
books they create programs they impact
people and they change families i've
seen my family changed by a coach and
course grader
an author and trainer and you are going
to be helping families as well
i see the results in the families that
have been changed that i've helped
it's time to start to realize the
potential in the business that you've
chosen
make your why bigger than just you
paying the bills and getting sales
make it the results that you deliver to
people and come from a place of how can
i help as many people as possible
reach their goals instead of being
afraid of oh do i look good do i sound
good did i say this right is my content
perfect
get it out of your head this idea of
perfection
it's a lie
[Music]
perfection is a lie perfectionism is one
of the biggest things that stops
course creators and coaches and trainers
from reaching their goals
imperfect action is what produces the
best results all right listen i hope
that you stay plugged into this podcast
i hope that you keep watching my videos
grow your life everybody and we'll talk
soon have a good one